Finding Aid for Seaman-Patrick Paper Company records, 1905-1922.
Detroit Public Library
Seaman-Patrick Paper Company records,
1905-1922.
Detroit Public Library. Burton Historical Collection.
03543
MS/Seaman-Patrick Paper Company.
Seaman-Patrick Paper Company.
46 Linear ft. (8 boxes, 62 volumes, 1 large manuscript)
This collection contains records of the company, from its early days as Bermingham-Seaman-Patrick Co., to accounts up to the 1980s. Personal papers include those of Robert A. Patrick and the Forest W. Starling family.
Biographical/Historical note
The Bermingham Seaman Company of Chicago, with George M. Seaman as president, was one of the largest paper jobbers in the county. When they decided to open a Detroit office in 1911, they sought out Robert A. Patrick, a young Detroiter who was well known in the paper trade. The Detroit Corporation was called Bermingham-Seaman-Patrick Company, with Mr. Patrick serving as president and manager. In 1917 the name Seaman-Patrick Paper Company was adopted for the Detroit house, and the Chicago firm was known as the Seaman Paper Company. The Detroit organization, under the management of Mr. Patrick, quickly reached the point of being the largest wholesale paper business in the State of Michigan, dealing in fine printing papers exclusively. After Mr. Patrick died in 1920, Forrest W. Starling managed the company. Located at the corner of Cass and Larned Streets in Detroit, Mich., the Seaman-Patrick Paper Co. moved to 1225 Vermont Ave. in Jan. 1925. George Seaman remained president of the company throughout the early 1920s. By 1928 John G. Starling was president. His son Forrest was treasurer and general Manager. As of 2008, the company still exists, located at 2065 W. Fort St. in Detroit, Mich.
Biographical/Historical note
Robert Alexander Patrick was born in Detroit on Feb. 5, 1881. In 1812 he was married to Mary G. Everson and they had two children. Mr. Patrick died of pneumonia on Feb. 6, 1920, at the age of 39.
Arrangement note
Organized by Series: I. Corporation records. II. Related companies. III. Personal papers.
Restrictions
This collection is open for research use as of Feb. 22, 2008.
Other finding aids note
Finding aid and white index cards available in the Burton Historical Collection and on the World Wide Web.
Selected Search Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Patrick, Robert Alexander, 1881-1920.
Starling family
Seaman-Patrick Paper Company -- Archives.
Vermont Realty Investment Co.
Bermingham Seaman Company.
Bermingham-Seaman-Patrick Company.
Seaman Paper Company.
Paper industry -- Michigan -- Detroit.
Real estate agents -- Vermont.
Small business investment companies -- Vermont.
Account books. -- aat
Business records. -- aat
Financial records. -- aat
Photographs. -- aat
Clippings (information artifacts). -- aat
Personal correspondence. -- aat
Stock certificates. -- aat
Container List
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Corporation Records
  Scope and Contents note
  This series concerns the Seaman-Patrick Paper Company's financial records, legal papers, time books and correspondence.
  - Account Book, 1908-1912 (Box:file 1:1)
    - 1919, L-Z (Box:item 1:2)
    - 1921-1962 (Box:item 1:3)
    - 1932 (Box:item 1:4)
  - Bills Receivable, 1928-1940 (Box:file 1:5)
  - Canceled Checks, 1930-1949 (Box:file 1:6)
  - Check Stubs, 1911-1915 (Box:file 1:7)
  - Corporation Records (Box:file 1:8)
    - Insurance Papers, 1918-1961 (Box:item 1:9)
  - Corporation Records—Legal Papers; Court Case, 1923-1926 (Box:file 2:1)
  - Correspondence/Miscellaneous, 1916-1917; n.d. (Box:file 2:2)
  - International Hospital Record, 1909-1910 (Box:file 2:3)
  - Invoices/Orders, 1924-1946 (Box:file 2:4)
  - National Insurance Register, 1924-1960 (Box:file 2:5)
  - Notes and Bills—Payable, 1915-1916 (Box:file 2:6)
    - Receivable, 1907-1914 (Box:item 2:7)
    - 1924-1927 (Box:item 2:8)
  - Receipts, 1912-1924 (Box:file 2:9)
  - Report Sheets, 1923 (Box:file 2:10)
  - Stock Ledger, 1923-1936 (Box:file 3:1)
  - Stockholders/Proxies, 1963-1965 (Box:file 3:2)
  - Material from Time Books (see Volumes for Time Books), 1920-1922 (Box:file 3:3)
    - 1925-1931 (Box:item 3:4)
    - 1951-1953 (Box:item 3:5)
  - Sub-series A: Stock Certificates
    - 1921-1923 (Box:item 3:6)
    - 1923-1924 (Box:item 3:7)
    - 1923-1930 (Box:item 3:8)
    - Stock Certificates, 1923-1928 (Box:item 4:)
    - 1931-1936 (Box:item 5:1)
    - 1941-1963 (Box:item 5:2)
- Series II: Related Companies
  Before his connection with the Bermingham-Seaman Paper Company, Robert A. Patrick worked for F.S. Dresskell andCompany. After Mr. Dresskcll's retirement in 1908, the company was renamed Dresskell Paper Company, and Mr. Patrick was appointed manager of the new undertaking. Papers from this company are included in this series, along with other companies such as Carpenter Paper Company and Vermont Realty andInvestment Company.
  - Carpenter Paper Company, 1935-1936 (see also Volumes) (Box:file 5:3)
  - Dresskell Paper Company (see also Volumes)—Stock Certificates, 1908-1910 (Box:file 5:4)
  - Evans-Winter-Hebb, 1928-1942 (Box:file 5:5)
  - Vermont Building andLand company, 1928-1930 (Box:file 5:6)
    - Stock Certificates, 1928 (Box:item 5:7)
  - Sub-series A: Bermingham-Seaman-Patrick Company (sec also Volumes)
    - Check Book, 1933 (Box:item 5:8)
    - Payroll, 1917; 1919 (Box:item 6:1)
    - Stock Certificates, 1911-1921 (Box:item 6:2)
  - Sub-series B: Vermont Realty andInvestment Company (see also Volumes)
    - Abstracts of Title—Lefferty Farm (Box:item 6:3)
    - Johnson's Subdivision, Lots 17, 18 and19 (Box:item 6:4)
      - Johnston s Subdivision, Lots 20 and21 (Box:item 6:5)
      - Lot 22 (Box:item 6:6)
      - Lots 23, 24, 24 and26 (Box:item 6:7)
    - Account Book, 1928-1961 (Box:item 6:8)
    - Agreements, 1960 (Box:item 6:9)
    - Bank Statements, 1967-1968 (Box:item 6:10)
    - Corporation Papers, 1920-1956 (Box:item 7:1)
    - Electrical Trades Specifications, 1960 (Box:item 7:2)
    - Land Records, 1936-1951 (Box:item 7:3)
    - Proxies, 1960-1965 (Box:item 7:4)
    - Stock Certificates, 1928-1929 (Box:item 7:5)
      - 1929 (Box:item 7:6)
- Series III: Personal Papers (See also LMS)
  Biographical/Historical note
  Robert Alexander Patrick was born in Detroit on February 5, 1881. In 1912 he was married to Mary G. Everson and they had two children. Mr. Patrick died of pneumonia on February 6, 1920, at the age of 39. Personal papers for Mr. And Mrs. Patrick include receipts and insurance papers.
  The Starling family features prominently in the Seaman-Patrick Paper Company story. John G. Starling served as president in the late 1920s; his son Forrest began as a salesman and worked his way up to company executive. Forrest W. Starling, who retired from S.P.P.C. in 1972, died in May 1973. His son, William, was Board Chairman of S.P.P.C., having worked for the company for fifty years before his retirement in 1995. William Starling, of Grosse Ile, died on December 20, 1998 at the age of eighty-six. Personal papers of the Starling family include audio-video materials, newspaper clippings and photographs.
  - Mr. and Mrs. Robert Alexander Patrick, 1916-1918 (Box:file 7:7)
  - Edythe Searle Starling, 1932-1945 (Box:file 7:8)
  - Audio/Video Materials—Audio Cassette Tapes: (Box:file 7:9)
    - Starling Distress (Box:item 7:9)
    - Gintzig (Box:item 7:9)
  - 8 mm Sound Movie Film: Bermuda (Box:file 7:10)
    - Gintzig (6 reels) (Box:item 7:10)
    - Life on the Farm, 1982 (Box:item 7:10)
    - Mess-up (Box:item 7:10)
    - New Year's Eve (Box:item 7:10)
    - Traders Party (Box:item 7:10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box:file 8:1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1953 (Box:file 8:2)
  - Photographs—Dated/Identified, 1947-1953 (Box:file 8:3)
    - Dated/Unidentified, [1920s]-1992 (Box:item 8:4)
    - Identified/Undated (Box:item 8:5)
    - Unidentified/Undated—Babies and Children (Box:item 8:6)
    - Dogs/Scenes and Houses (Box:item 8:7)
    - Groups (Box:item 8:8)
    - Men andBoys (Box:item 8:9)
    - Women andGirls/Adults with Children (Box:item 8:10)
- Plans, Starling Residence
- Account Books
- Mills, 1908-1915
  - 1912-1915
  - 1913-1915
  - 1914-1915, J-Z
  - 1928-1962
  - 1969-1982
  - 1980-1983
- Cash Journals
  - 1922-1926
  - 1927-1932
  - 1933-1938
  - 1940-1945
  - 1946-1952
  - 1957-1960
  - 1963
- Detroit Balance Books
  - 1912
  - 1912-1913
  - 1914-1915
- Dividends, 1928-1935
- Financial Statements
  - 1961-1968
  - 1969-1975
- General Journal, 1968-1975
- Ledger, 1914
- Letter Books
  - 1905
  - 1905-1906
- Minute Books
  - 1946-1963
  - 1962-1971
  - 1979-1982
- Purchase record, 1954-1962
- Record book, 1962
- Sales ledger, 1915-1916
- Sales ledger transfer, 1915-1916
- Salesman's profit sharing record
  - 1920-1922
  - 1922
- Time Books
  - 1916-1921
  - 1920-1922
  - 1922-1926
  - 1925-1931
  - 1926-1933
  - 1933-1940
  - 1937-1942
  - 1948-1951
  - 1951-1953
- Trial Balance, 1941-1963
- Bermingham-Seaman-Patrick Paper Company
  - Cash Journal, 1912-1914
  - Check Books
    - 1913
    - 1914
    - 1915
  - Purchase Ledger, 1915-1916
  - Purchase Records
    - 1911-1912
    - 1912-1913
    - 1913-1914
    - 1914-1915
    - 1916-1919
  - Sales Records
    - 1912-1913
    - 1913
    - 1913-1914
    - 1914-1915
    - 1915-1916
- Carpenter Paper Company
  - Appraisal
- F.S. Dresskell Paper Company
  - Cash Book, 1909-1912
  - Check Book, 1908-1909
- Vermont Realty and Investment Company Stockholders Meetings, 1970-1978